## Marcus Szabo



## marcus.szabo@outlook.com 6049282017

marcusgames.dev www.linkedin.com/in/marcus-szabo-76b77a19b

# Profile (Summary

A driven designer and developer with a love of 3D modeling and animating. Has experience with various design projects in the past using Unreal Engine, Unity and Maya and game development at a professional capacity. A skilled and competitive player with a wide knowledge of game mechanics, level layouts and feedback gameplay loops. A drive to create games that reward players for skilled plays, poses unique and challenging puzzles and encounters and encourages collaboration and teamwork in companies and communities.

#### Skills (

- Maya modeling/animation
- Unity
- Unreal Engine
- Blueprinting
- Processing

- Project Management
- Game/Level/Puzzle Design
- Team Leadership/Collaboration
- Perforce
- Jira task flow

# Work Experience

### **Brass Token**The Chant

#### September 2018 - November 2022

- Built up almost all of the **collision** and **streaming** through the map.
- Was lead on some key location level design, "airlock areas" and puzzle design.
- Designed and implemented a series of unique combat encounters.
- Assisted with enemy pathing and tethers.
- o Competency in Unreal Engine world editing and Blueprinting
- Performed Motion Capture movements for the character Jess and Ram Cultist.

#### **NVRC** Supervisor Lifeguard/Swim Instructor

December 2016 - Present

- Supervised a team of 2-8 lifeguards in high pressure first aid scenarios.
- Excellent experience with personal relations and diffusing conflict.

#### **Education** (

Simon Fraser University, Burnaby/Coquitlam, British Columbia, Canada Bachelor of Arts and Social Sciences in Interactive Arts and Technologies (2016-2023)

#### Relevant Projects

#### • AI Affective Virtual Human (Directed Studies)

A real-time reactive **AI** that uses an animated human **Avatar** that listens, thinks, and responds to the user, led by **Steve DiPaola**.

- Created **20+** unique animations for the Al's actions using **Maya**.
- Led a team of 4 animators to set deadlines, manage files, and create animations.

#### • Invasive (Interactive Arts and Technology 410)

A horror puzzle game for the IAT 410 advanced design class. Created through Unreal Engine and Maya.

- Modeled, rigged, and designed movement, death, and attack animations for 5 different characters within 6 weeks.
- Mapped out 4 levels and 5 puzzles for the game.

# Additional (Accomplishments

- Received awards for a business project "Mouse Trap" at Opp Fest 2022
- Achieved various National Level Time Standards in Competitive Swimming
- Achieved level of **Twitch Affiliate** as a video game streamer